# **JU YOUNG KIM**

juyoung.kim517@gmail.com +821076460746 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ju-young-kim-048215b6 GitHub Resume: https://juyoungkimthedev.github.io/resume

#### Summary

I have 5 years of software engineering experience mostly in fast-paced and agile startup companies with focus in fintech ranging from banking and insurance to payments. I have lots of hands-on experience building RESTful web services and ETL data pipeline for machine learning platforms. I have strong teamwork spirit and ethics and I plan to use these skills together with clean and efficient coding strategies to improve company processes and provide most optimal solutions for clients.

### Experience

#### Primer | Backend Software Engineer | London, United Kingdom

#### February 2022 - Present

- Worked in the core payment application framework team. Developed and maintained Starlette based Python application framework to allow developers to build internal and third-party apps on the payment platform. These apps were the building blocks of the payment platform. Led migration of old apps (not using framework) to the new framework.
- Maintained and improved existing FastAPI based core API by adding new endpoints, handlers and controllers that manage internal and third-party application lifecycle. Tools used: Aiohttp, SQLAlchemy, Kafka.
- Created marketplace API service that connects to the core API to serve app instances and specifications to merchants through a web dashboard, allowing complete app management on the dashboard.
- Reduced time to build and maintain new apps by 80% by creating an automation tool to manage app creation and metadata updates, eliminating frequent alembic data migrations and manual assets upload to S3.

#### Root | Software Engineer | Cape Town, South Africa

#### April 2021 - January 2022

- Joined the product team and worked mostly on the server side TypeScript/Node.js code to build new features and maintain a monolith insurance platform. Maintained some frontend dashboard components using React.js.
- Implemented policy pdf document encryption using Node.js qpdf wrapper that automatically password protects policy related documents before sending to clients.
- Ported client product module code execution environment from Node.js vm2 to AWS Lambda functions to allow for more secure code execution and dependency management.
- Improved the legacy React codebase by refactoring to the new internal web architecture. Mostly worked on changing class component code to functional component with React hooks.

#### Praelexis | Software Engineer & Data Engineer | Cape Town, South Africa

#### March 2018 - March 2021

- Designed, implemented and deployed highly scalable Python APIs in the Azure Kubernetes Service that serve multiple financial machine learning model scores for credit teams at a retail bank. Tools used: Flask, Aiohttp, Cosmos DB.
- Created and managed batch data pipelines handling financial transaction data of 10-100 million rows daily, used by
  machine learning workflows to perform model training, scoring and exporting. Tools used: Luigi, Azure HDInsight, Livy,
  PySpark, Spark SQL, Databricks.
- Contributed to migrating the bank's core data lake services built on top of Azure to AWS using S3, Glue, EMR, Lambda.

## Education

- University of Cape Town: **Master of Science**: Bioinformatics, 2018
- University of Pretoria: **Bachelor of Science Honors** in Bioinformatics, 2014
- University of Pretoria: Bachelor of Science in Biochemistry, 2013

#### **Technical Skills**

- Languages: Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Julia, R, Go.
- Frameworks and Libraries: FastAPI, Flask, Aiohttp, SQLAlchemy, Node.js, Express.js, React.js.
- Database: PostgreSQL, CosmosDB, DynamoDB.
- Cloud and DevOps: AWS (S3, Lambda, ECR), Azure (Blobstore, AKS), Docker, Kubernetes, Rancher, Helm, Terraform.
- Data: Azure HDInsight, Databricks, PySpark, Apache Kafka.
- Tools: Git, GitLab, Pipeline CI/CD, BitBucket, JIRA, Localstack, VS Code, Postman, PyCharm, Datadog, Feature flags.